《权力的游戏》
前情回顾
如果七大王国
What if the Seven Kingdoms
由一位公正的女性和一位正直的男性共同统治 会怎样呢？
were ruled by a just woman and an honorable man?
你真名叫伊耿·坦格利安
You're Aegon Targaryen...
是铁王座的真正继承人
true heir to the Iron Throne.
与生俱来
You've always been.
她不需要成为我的朋友
She doesn't need to be my friend.
但我是她的女王
But I am her queen.
我们必须要并肩作战
We must fight together now...
否则我们都会死
or die.
想想我为爱情都做了什么
The things I do for love.
m -11 -35 l -11 39 l 63 39 l 63 -35
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
翻译 季叽馥疾己
翻译 Oliviazqm
绝境长城  the Wall
翻译 LittleFireAidan
翻译 Taffy的北境雪诺
最后壁炉城Last Hearth
翻译 黑特泽沃儿德
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
https://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com
m 31 -6 l -21 40 l 34 22 m 29 -8 l -3 -12 l -24 40
翻译 玫瑰叔
临冬城Winterfell
翻译 依依Eva
校对 北落师门
校对 玫瑰叔
监制 临冬城的狮子
监制 北落师门
临冬城的地窖Crypt of Winterfell
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com          Heichengbao
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
君临 King's Landing
字幕组发起人 baozhenyuawabi
策划 衣柜军团
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
灰机GAME  开拓你的世界
红堡Red Keep
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
m -18.625 0 l -18.625 0 l 281.25 0 l 281.25 1.125 l -18.625 1.125
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第二集
七王国的骑士
A Knight of the Seven Kingdoms
本字幕的制作目的是为了相关爱好者交流学习之用，
请在下载24小时之内删除。请勿用于任何商业用途。
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
在我小时候 我的哥哥会给我讲睡前故事
When I was a child,my brother would tell me a bedtime story...
从前有个杀害了我们父王的人
about the man who murdered our father.
他从背后刺中父王 割破他的喉咙
Who stabbed him in the back and cut his throat.
他坐在铁王座上 眼睁睁看着
Who sat down on the Iron Throne and watched
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” “龙之母”
父王的鲜血在地上流淌
as his blood poured onto the floor.
哥哥还给我讲过其他故事
He told me other stories as well.
说到我们夺回七大王国之后
About all the things we would do to that man...
这个人落入我们手中时
once we took back the Seven Kingdoms
处置他的种种方式
and had him in our grasp.
你姐姐承诺过派兵来北方
Your sister pledged to send her army north.
她是说过
She did.
我可没看见什么军队
I don't see an army.
我只看到一个人 还只有一只手
I see one man, with one hand.
看来你姐姐骗了我
It appears your sister lied to me.
她也骗了我
She lied to me as well.
她从未想过派兵北上
She never had any intention of sending her army north.
她有了攸伦·葛雷乔伊的舰队和两万名精兵
She has Euron Greyjoy's fleet and 20,000 fresh troops.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 女王之手
她花钱雇佣来的
The Golden Company from Essos,
厄斯索斯的黄金团
bought and paid for.
即使我们击败了尸鬼大军
Even if we defeat the dead,
她仍有足够的兵力击溃幸存的人
she'll have more than enough to destroy the survivors.
“我们”？
"We"?
我发誓要为生者战斗
I promised to fight for the living.
我希望能恪守誓言
I intend to keep that promise.
- 陛下 我了解我哥哥 - 就像了解你姐姐那样深？
- Your Grace,I know my brother... - Like you knew your sister?
他独自北上 很清楚会受到怎样的对待
He came here alone, knowing full well how he'd be received.
如果他刚才说的不是实情 那他还何必如此？
Why would he do that if he weren't telling the truth?
大概是相信在他割破我的喉咙前
Perhaps he trusts his little brother to defend him,
弟弟会一直为自己辩护吧
right up to the moment he slits my throat.
您是对的 我们不能轻信他
You're right. We can't trust him.
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵夫人
他曾当街袭击我的父亲
He attacked my father in the streets.
他想让我们家破人亡
He tried to destroy my house and my family,
所做之恶不比对您家族的少
the same as he did yours.
你想让我道歉么？
Do you want me to apologize?
别想了
I won't.
当时我们在交战
We were at war.
我的所作所为 都是为了我的家族 我的家人
Everything I did, I did for my house and my family.
再来一遍我还是一样
I'd do it all again.
布兰·史塔克
绿先知
想想我们为爱都做了什么
The things we do for love.
那为什么你现在抛弃了你的家族和家人呢？
So why have you abandoned your house and family now?
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
因为现在已经不是忠于谁的问题了
Because this goes beyond loyalty.
现在关乎的是生死
This is about survival.
陛下 您不怎么了解我
You don't know me well, Your Grace.
但我了解詹姆爵士
But I know Ser Jaime.
他是个有荣誉感的人
He is a man of honor.
我曾俘虏过他
I was his captor once.
但是后来我们遭到绑架
But when we were both taken prisoner
当那帮人企图强奸我的时候
and the men holding us tried to force themselves on me,
詹姆爵士保护了我
Ser Jaime defended me.
还因此失去一只手
And lost his hand because of it.
夫人 没有他您可能就活不成了
Without him, my lady, you would not be alive.
他给了我武器和盔甲
He armed me, armored me,
派我去追踪您的下落 带您回家
and sent me to find you and bring you home
因为他向您母亲发过誓
because he'd sworn an oath to your mother.
你在为他做担保？
You vouch for him?
是的
I do.
你会和他并肩作战么？
You would fight beside him?
会的
I would.
我将性命托付于你
I trust you with my life.
若你也敢托付给他
If you trust him with yours,
那我们应当接纳他
we should let him stay.
北境守护意下如何？
What does the Warden of the North say about it?
琼恩·雪诺
伊耿·坦格利安 铁王座法理继承人
我们需要尽可能地招揽人手
We need every man we can get.
那好吧
Very well.
灰虫子
无垢者的指挥官
谢谢陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
你是不是知道瑟曦在撒谎 还帮她圆谎
Either you knew Cersei was lying and let me believe otherwise,
还是说你压根就不知道我们被骗了
or you didn't know at all.
反正你要么是个叛徒 要么是个傻子
Which makes you either a traitor or a fool.
- 我是傻子 - 也不是第一回了
- I was a fool. - Not for the first time.
瑟曦还坐在那王座上
Cersei still sits on the throne.
如果你不能帮我夺回来
If you can't help me take it back,
首相我就另找高明
I'll find another Hand who can.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
女王铁卫 “大熊”
估计战事结束前 这首相徽章的主人
I suspect one of you will be wearing this
就要从你俩当中选了
before it's all over.
詹德利
劳勃国王的私生子 “大牛”
艾莉亚·史塔克
你就没别的事可干了么？
Don't you have something better to do?
我的武器你做好没？
You make my weapon yet?
等我弄完手头几千把这玩意儿就动手
Just as soon as I'm done making a few thousand of these.
你应该先给我造
You should make mine first.
还要确保比这个再结实点
And make sure it's stronger than this.
够结实了吧
It's strong enough.
你知道吧 下到墓窖里会更安全的
It's going to be safer down in the crypt,you know.
你要去墓窖么？
Are you going to be down in the crypt?
- 不去 但 - 但你是个战士
- No, but... - But you're a fighter.
我打的尸鬼够多了
I've done my share.
你和尸鬼战斗过？
You've fought them?
嗯 打过一些吧
I did. Some of them.
有多少？
How many?
没多少
A few.
对我而言也挺多了
That was enough.
它们什么样啊？
What are they like?
可怕
Bad.
非常可怕
Really bad.
“非常可怕”？
"Really bad"?
即便是铁匠学徒 也该能形容得比“非常可怕”形象一点吧
Even a smith's apprentice can do better than "really bad."
它们到底长什么样？身上什么味道？
What do they look like? What do they smell like?
怎么行动？彻底弄死它们有多难？
How do they move? How hard are they to kill?
听好 我知道你想战斗
Look, I know you want to fight.
知道你不怕什么强奸犯 杀人狂……
And I know you're not scared of rapers or murderers or...
但这次不一样 这次…
This is different. This is...
这次是死亡
This is death.
你想知道它们什么样？死亡的样子
You want to know what they're like? Death.
死亡 死神 反正就是那副模样
That's what they're like.
我见识过死神
I know Death.
他有千张面孔
He's got many faces.
很期待见见他这一张脸呢
I look forward to seeing this one.
- 姐的武器呢？- 这就动手
- My weapon? - I'll get right on it.
我很抱歉把你推下塔楼
I'm sorry for what I did to you.
你当初并无歉意
You weren't sorry then.
你在维护自己的家人
You were protecting your family.
我已经不是那样的人了
I'm not that person anymore.
如果不是你当初把我推下去
You still would be,
你现在依旧是那样的人
if you hadn't pushed me out of that window.
而我可能还是布兰登·史塔克
And I would still be Brandon Stark.
- 你现在不是么？- 不是了
- You're not? - No.
我现在是另一种存在
I'm something else now.
你不怪我
You're not angry at me.
我不怪任何人
I'm not angry at anyone.
你为什么没告诉他们？
Why didn't you tell them?
如果我让他们先杀了你
You won't be able to help us in this fight
你就不能在这场大战中助我们一臂之力了
if I let them murder you first.
那大战之后呢？
What about afterwards?
你怎么知道我们能活到大战之后？
How do you know there is an afterwards?
在地上做个记号！
Put a marker in the ground!
把它送到城墙上去
Bring it up to the wall!
好的 送到城墙上去
Up to the wall. All right.
得 我们都到这儿来了
Well, here we are.
是呀 我们都到这儿来了
Yes, here we are.
又在一起了
Together again.
群众还挺喜闻乐见
And the masses rejoice.
他们怎么看待他们的新女王？
How do they feel about their new queen?
她也是你的新女王
She's your new queen too.
他们记得上次坦格利安家族
They remember what happened
带着龙北上时 发生过什么
the last time Targaryens brought dragons north.
一旦他们发现
They'll come around
丹妮莉丝与她的祖先不一样 他们会回心转意的
once they see Daenerys is different.
那她真的是吗？不一样？
And she is? Different?
她不一样
She is.
- 你这么相信她？- 是的
- You're sure about her? - I am.
她似乎没有那么相信你
She didn't seem sure about you.
这不怪她
It's hard to blame her.
我犯了一个聪明人常犯的错误
I made a mistake common to clever people.
- 我低估了我的对手 - 嗯
- I underestimated my opponents. - Hmm.
瑟曦告诉我这次怀孕改变了她
Cersei told me the pregnancy had changed her.
她说这是一个让你们俩都重新开始的契机
A chance for you both to start again.
而我相信了她
And I believed her.
怀孕这事也是她捏造的吗？
Was she lying about the baby too?
不 那个倒是真的
No, that part is real.
她一直很擅长利用事实来编造谎话
She's always been good at using the truth to tell lies.
不用太自责
I wouldn't be too hard on yourself.
我被她骗得最苦
She's fooled me more than anybody.
怎么了？
What?
你从来没被她骗过
She never fooled you.
你一直都很清楚她是怎样的人
You always knew exactly what she was,
但你依然爱她
and you loved her anyway.
看来……
So...
……我们要死在临冬城了
...we're going to die at Winterfell.
这不是我原本计划的死法
Not the death I would've chosen.
我一直想象我80岁的时候
I always pictured myself
躺在自己床上
dying in my own bed,
行将就木
the age of 80,
- 喝饱了酒 还有 - ……一个姑娘
- with a belly full of wine and -  ...a girl's mouth
- 帮你吹箫 - 帮我吹箫
- around your cock. - around my cock.
至少瑟曦无法亲手杀死我
At least Cersei won't get to murder me.
当我正被尸鬼撕碎的时候
I'm sure I'll feel some satisfaction
想到剥夺了她这一乐趣
denying her that pleasure
肯定会感到某种满足
while I'm being ripped apart by dead men.
或许等我死了以后……
Maybe after I'm dead...
我会南下进军君临城
I'll march down to King's Landing
然后撕碎瑟曦
and rip her apart.
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
很好 对 瞄准
Good. Yes, aim.
别急
Don't rush.
上前来
Come forward.
- 来呀 - 詹姆爵士
- Come on. - Ser Jaime.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
- 他进步很大 - 凑合吧
- He's come a long way. - He's all right.
再来一次 快点
One more time. Come on.
- 需要学习的还很多 - 你肯定会教他的
- Still has a lot to learn. - I'm sure you'll teach him.
我听说你将指挥左翼部队
I've been told you're commanding the left flank.
是的
I am.
这个 呃……地形不错
It's, uh... It's good ground.
是的
It is.
那个斜坡 会对我们有利
The rise, it should give us some advantage.
如果能保持紧密的队形
If we can keep a tight formation,
我们或许有机会击退他们
we might be able to beat them back.
是 你说得对
Yes, I think you're right.
- 你怎么回事？ - 什么？
- What are you doing? - What?
- 我想你应该知道 - 我真的不知道
- I think you know. - I truly don't.
我们从来没有哪次交谈 这么半天了
We have never had a conversation last this long
你都没侮辱我 一次也没有
without you insulting me. Not once.
你希望我侮辱你？
You want me to insult you?
- 当然不！- 那不就好了
- No! - Good.
我到临冬城是因为……
I came to Winterfell because...
虽然我不是从前那个战士了
I'm not the fighter I used to be.
但是能在你的指挥下战斗 我会倍感荣耀
But I'd be honored to serve under your command,
如果你愿意接纳我的话
if you'll have me.
我得回去了
I better get back.
抱歉 卡丽熙
Forgive me, khaleesi.
你做了什么冒犯我的事吗？
Have you done something to offend me?
很多
Many things.
那都是很久以前的事了 而且我早就原谅你了
Long ago and long forgiven.
但就算我犯下过失
But you did forgive,
你仍然原谅了我
despite my failures.
当我听说你任命了提利昂为御前首相
When I heard you'd named Tyrion your Hand,
我的心都碎了
it broke my heart.
我任命他为首相的时候
When I named him Hand,
并不知道我能否再见到你
I didn't know if I'd ever see you again.
你做出了正确的选择
You made the right choice.
在我的印象中 你不是很喜欢他
I wasn't under the impression you liked him very much.
确实
I didn't.
我们从瓦兰提斯到弥林那一路上
His mouth hardly stopped moving
他一直喋喋不休
between Volantis and Meereen.
我强忍着才没将他丢进海里
It was all I could do not to throw him in the sea.
但在那些油腔滑调背后 他的聪明才智……
But the mind behind all those words...
他犯了错误
He's made mistakes.
很严重的错误
Serious mistakes.
我们都犯过错
As have we all.
他有自己的过失
He owns his
然后从中吸取教训
and learns from them.
你在建议我宽恕
You're advising me to forgive the man
那个抢占你位置的人？
who stole your position?
是的
I am.
如果您允许的话
And one other suggestion,
我还有一个谏言
if you'll allow me.
等到所有步兵都被调派到战场上
The moment we can get the last infantryman
我们就应该马上关闭城门
out onto the field, we should shut the gates.
尽你的全力让城门多开一会
Keep them open for as long as you can.
还有人正从郊外逃难而来
There are still people coming in from the countryside.
约恩·罗伊斯
“青铜” 谷地领主
珊莎夫人 我希望我们可以私下谈谈
Lady Sansa, I was hoping we could speak alone.
我之前本以为
I thought you and I
就快和你达成共识了
were on the verge of agreement before.
关于詹姆爵士的问题
About Ser Jaime.
布蕾妮一直对我很忠诚
Brienne has been loyal to me, always.
她是我最信任的人
I trust her more than anyone.
真希望我也能如此信任我的顾问
I wish I could have that kind of faith in my advisors.
提利昂是个好人
Tyrion is a good man.
他对我一向彬彬有礼
He was never anything but decent towards me.
我任命他为首相 不只因为他是个好人
I didn't ask him to be my Hand simply because he was good.
我任命他为我的首相
I asked him to be my Hand
是因为他是个有头脑的好人
because he was good, and intelligent,
而且必要时 他也会变得无情
and ruthless when he had to be.
他一开始就不应该相信瑟曦
He never should have trusted Cersei.
您也不应该相信她
You never should have either.
我以为他了解他的姐姐
I thought he knew his sister.
家家有本难念的经
Families are complicated.
我的家族也是如此
Ours certainly have been.
可悲的共同点
A sad thing to have in common.
我们两个还有其他的共同点
We have other things in common.
我们都知道作为女性领导者的艰难
We've both known what it means to lead people
领导那些不愿意屈服于女人的人
who aren't inclined to accept a woman's rule.
而且在我来看
And we've both done a damn good job of it,
我们都做得很好
from what I can tell.
尽管如此 我还是感受到了我们之间有些不睦
And yet, I can't help but feel we're at odds with one another.
为什么？
Why is that?
因为你哥哥
Your brother.
他爱您 您是知道的
He loves you, you know that.
但是这点困扰着你
That bothers you.
男人会为女人做蠢事
Men do stupid things for women.
他们很容易受女人摆布
They're easily manipulated.
我这一生只有一个目标：
All my life, I've known one goal:
铁王座
the Iron Throne.
我要把它从毁掉我家族的敌人手里夺回来
Taking it back from the people who destroyed my family,
这个敌人也几乎毁掉你的家族
and almost destroyed yours.
我只与他们为敌
My war was against them.
直到我遇到了琼恩
Until I met Jon.
如今我在这里 在半个世界之外
Now I'm here, half a world away,
在琼恩的战争中与他并肩作战
fighting Jon's war alongside him.
你来告诉我 到底是谁受谁的摆布？
Tell me, who manipulated whom?
你当初一抵达临冬城时我就应该向您表示感谢
I should have thanked you the moment you arrived.
这是我的错
That was a mistake.
我来这里 是因为我爱上了你哥哥……
I'm here because I love your brother...
因为我相信他……
and I trust him...
还因为我知道他是个恪守承诺的人
and I know he's true to his word.
在我生命中 他是仅有的第二个
He's only the second man in my life
能让我这么评价的男人
I can say that about.
第一个是谁？
Who was the first?
某个比他高点儿的人
Someone taller.
那么之后呢？
And what happens afterwards?
当我们消灭了尸鬼大军 打败了瑟曦
We defeat the dead, we destroy Cersei.
之后呢？
What happens then?
我夺回铁王座
I take the Iron Throne.
那么北境呢？
What about the North?
敌人从我们手中夺走北境
It was taken from us,
我们又亲手将它夺回
and we took it back.
我们也曾说过 北境永远不再向任何人俯首称臣
And we said we'd never bow to anyone else again.
到时候 您将如何处置北境？
What about the North?
抱歉打扰了  夫人 陛下……
Apologies, my lady.Your Grace...
什么事？
What is it?
席恩·葛雷乔伊
女王陛下
My queen.
你姐姐呢？
Your sister?
她只剩下了几艘船
She only has a few ships,
也没法把船开来这里
and she couldn't sail them here.
所以她去了铁群岛
So she's sailing to the Iron Islands instead,
她将以您的名义夺回铁群岛
to take them back in your name.
你为什么没有和她一起回去？
But why aren't you with her?
我想为临冬城作战 珊莎公爵夫人……
I want to fight for Winterfell, Lady Sansa...
如果您允许的话
if you'll have me.
佬爷 我们不是当兵的
Milord, we're not soldiers.
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
你们现在都是了
You are now.
听着 我活了大半辈子
Look, I made it through most of my years
连战场的边儿都没蹭到
without ever getting near a fight,
但之后我却在私生子之战里活下来了
but then I survived the Battle of the Bastards.
就在那道城墙之外
Right outside these walls.
既然我能从那儿活下来 你们也能活下去
If I can live through that,you can live through this.
他们会在锻造处给你们武器和装备
They'll outfit you with weapons at the forge.
就在那边
Right that way.
谢谢您
Thank you.
当大战来临时 你们在墓窖里躲好
When the time comes,you'll be down in the crypts.
那里是最安全的地方
They're the safest place to be.
吉莉
山姆威尔的爱人
穿过那扇拱门就是了
Through that archway right over there.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我应该往哪边去？
Which way should I go?
你想去哪边？
Which way do you want to go?
所有的孩子到时候
All the children will be going below
都会待在墓窖里
when the time comes.
但是我的两个哥哥曾经都是战士
But both me brothers were soldiers.
我也想上战场
I want to fight too.
说得好啊
That's good to hear.
到时候我会和我的儿子一起待在墓窖里
I'm going to be in the crypt with my son,
如果能和你待在一起 有你保护我们
and I'd feel a lot better with you down there
- 我会感到更安全 - 很多人都会这样觉得
- to protect us.- I'm sure a lot of people would.
好呀 那我就去保护墓窖里的人
All right.I'll defend the crypt, then.
骑手归来！
Riders coming in!
山姆威尔·塔利
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人指挥官
我亲爱的小乌鸦
My little crow.
托蒙德
“巨人克星”
我以为你死了
I thought we'd lost you.
差点
Almost.
贝里·唐德利恩
“闪电大王”
你们怎么碰到一起的？
How did you find each other?
我们在最后壁炉城碰面
We met up at the Last Hearth.
但是尸鬼大军先我们一步
The dead got there first.
安柏家的人呢？
The Umbers?
现在为夜王而战了
Fighting for the Night King now.
我们得绕过他们才回到这里
We had to travel around them to get here.
现在还没到这儿的
Whoever's not here now
都成了他们的一员
is with them.
我们还有多长时间？
How long do we have?
只到明早太阳升起之前
Before the sun comes up tomorrow.
大个子女人还在这儿吗？
The big woman still here?
他们就要来了
They're coming.
我们有龙晶
We have dragonglass
和瓦雷利亚钢
and Valyrian steel.
但它们的数量众多
But there are too many of them.
远远超过我们
Far too many.
我们的敌人不知疲倦
Our enemy doesn't tire.
不会停留
Doesn't stop.
没有感觉
Doesn't feel.
与它们硬碰硬的话我们没有胜算
We can't beat them in a straight fight.
那我们该怎么做？
So, what can we do?
它们都是被夜王转化的 听他的指挥
The Night King made them all.They follow his command.
如果夜王倒下……
If he falls...
干掉他应该是我们最好的机会
Getting to him may be our best chance.
如果这是真的 他绝对不会露面
If that's true,he'll never expose himself.
他会的
Yes, he will.
他会来找我的
He'll come for me.
他先前试过很多次  找到过很多三眼乌鸦
He's tried before, many times,with many Three-Eyed Ravens.
亚丽·卡史塔克
卡霍城伯爵夫人
为什么？
Why?
他究竟想要什么？
What does he want?
无尽的长夜
An endless night.
他想抹去这个世界 而我是这个世界的记忆
He wants to erase this world,and I am its memory.
那就是死亡的意义了 不是吗
That's what death is,isn't it?
忘记
Forgetting.
和被忘记
Being forgotten.
如果我们忘记了我们去过何地
If we forget where we've been
做过何事
and what we've done,
我们就不再是人了
we're not men anymore.
只是动物而已
Just animals.
你的记忆并不来自于书籍
Your memories don't come from books.
你的经历也不仅仅是简单的故事
Your stories aren't just stories.
如果我想抹除人类世界
If I wanted to erase the world of men,
我会先从你下手
I'd start with you.
夜王怎样能找到你？
How will he find you?
我身上有他的标记
His mark is on me.
他一直都知道我在哪
He always knows where I am.
我们会把你安置在墓窖中
We'll put you in the crypt,
- 那里是最安全的 - 不
- where it's safest. - No.
我们需要在他的军队彻底毁灭我们之前
We need to lure him into the open
把他引诱到开阔地带
before his army destroys us all.
我会在神木林等着他
I'll wait for him in the Godswood.
你想让我们把你当作诱饵？
You want us to use you as bait?
我们不会把你自己扔在那里
We're not leaving you alone out there.
他不是一个人 我会和他在一起
He won't be. I'll stay with him.
还有所有的铁种
With the Ironborn.
我曾经从你手中夺走了这座城堡
I took this castle from you.
现在就让我来守护你
Let me defend you now.
我们会尽可能拖住其余的亡者大军
We'll hold off the rest of them for as long as we can.
时机到来之际
When the time comes,
我和戴佛斯爵士会在城墙上
Ser Davos and I will be on the walls,
给你们点燃战壕的信号
to give you the signal to light the trench.
戴佛斯爵士完全可以自己挥舞火把
Ser Davos is perfectly capable of waving a torch on his own.
你就待在墓窖里
You'll be in the crypt.
陛下 我也曾参加过战斗
Your Grace, I have fought before,
我可以再打一仗
I can do it again.
与那些冒着生命危险的
Alongside the men and women
男人和女人们一同战斗
risking their lives.
他们有成千上万人
There are thousands of them
可你只有一个
and only one of you.
你不能像他们一样勇猛地战斗
You can't fight as well as they can,
但你出谋划策比他们都厉害
but you can think better than any of them.
你在这里正是因为你机智过人
You're here because of your mind.
如果我们幸存下来 我还需要你的智慧
If we survive, I'll need it.
在战场上 巨龙应该能给我们带来一些优势
The dragons should give us an edge in the field.
如果巨龙在战场上 它们就没法保护布兰
If they're in the field, they're not protecting Bran.
我们得离布兰近一点
We need to be near him.
不能太近
Not too near,
否则夜王就不会来了
or the Night King won't come.
但要近到可以在夜王过来时追上他
But close enough to pursue him when he does.
龙焰能够挡住夜王吗？
Dragonfire will stop him?
我不知道
I don't know.
从来没人尝试过
No one's ever tried.
我们都要死了
We're all going to die.
但至少我们会死在一起
But at least we die together.
都去休息一会吧
Let's get some rest.
陛下 我先退下了
Your Grace.
需要帮忙吗？
Do you need help?
不用
No.
你经历了一段奇异的旅程
You've had a strange journey.
比大多数人都奇异些
Stranger than most.
我想听听这段故事
I'd like to hear about it.
说来话长
It's a long story.
只不过我们在这凛冬之时……
If only we were trapped in a castle...
被困在了城堡里 无处可去
in the middle of winter, with nowhere to go.
弥桑黛
女王的翻译和顾问
你好
Hello.
当丹妮莉丝夺得王位后……
When Daenerys takes her throne...
这里就没有我们的容身之处了
there will be no place for us here.
我效忠我的女王
I am loyal to my queen.
我会为她战斗 直到她的敌人被打败
I will fight for her until her enemies are defeated,
但当战争结束 她获胜后……
but when the war is over and she has won...
你想在这个地方一直到老吗？
do you want to grow old in this place?
你有没有其它想做的事情
Is there nothing else you want to do,
或者其它想去看看的地方？
nothing else you want to see?
纳斯岛
Naath.
我想再去看看那些海滩
I'd like to see the beaches again.
那我一定会带你去纳斯岛
Then I will take you there.
我家乡的人们都很温和
My people are peaceful.
我们都不能保护自己
We cannot protect ourselves.
我的人可不温和
My people are not peaceful.
我们会保护你们的
We will protect you.
白灵
琼恩·雪诺的冰原狼
你告诉她真相了吗？
Have you told her yet?
还没有
No.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
小心一些
Being careful.
看准你的时机
Biding your time.
等待最佳的……
Waiting for the perfect...
我们从今开始守望
And now our watch begins.
吉莉呢？ 还有小山姆呢？
Gilly? Little Sam?
他们在墓窖里会很安全
They'll be safe down in the crypt.
如果你想和他们在一起……
If you want to join them...
去保护他们
To protect them.
看来所有人都忘了
Everyone seems to forget that
我是第一个杀死异鬼的人
I was the first man to kill a White Walker.
- 我杀死过瑟恩人 - 就杀了一个
- I've killed Thenns. - Thenn.
我不止一次救过吉莉
I've saved Gilly more than once.
我从学城的图书馆里偷走过很多很多书
I stole a considerable number of books from the Citadel library,
我还从先民拳峰活了下来
survived the Fist of the First Men.
你们这里需要我
You need me out there.
如果真到了这个地步
Well, if that's what it's come to,
- 我们就真操蛋了 - 其实 说你被操蛋了
- we really are fucked. - Well, calling you "fucked"
并不完全准确
wouldn't be strictly accurate.
山姆威尔·塔利
Samwell Tarly.
异鬼杀手
Slayer of White Walkers.
妇女之友
Lover of Ladies.
这些征兆就足以表明
As if we needed any more signs
这个世界要完蛋了
the world was ending.
想当初
Think back to where we started.
有我们大家 还有葛兰和派普
Us, Grenn, Pyp.
如今只剩我们三个人了
Now it's just us three.
最后一个活着的 记得烧了另外两个
Last man left, burn the rest of us.
我真希望父亲也在这里
I wish Father were here.
我很想看看他脸上的表情
I would love to see the look on his face
当他意识到他的两个儿子
when he realizes his two sons
都将为了保护临冬城而死去
are about to die defending Winterfell.
那表情一定会很有趣
That would be something to see.
我还记得我们第一次来这儿
I remember the first time we were here,
我第一次看见这个大厅
the first time I saw this hall.
嗯
Mm.
你是头黄金雄狮
You were a golden lion.
我是个醉醺醺的嫖客
I was a drunken whoremonger.
一切都是那么简单
It was all so simple.
远没有那么简单
It wasn't so simple.
我还在和我姐姐上床
I was sleeping with my sister
而你在这世上还只有一个朋友
and you had one friend in the world
一个和他姐姐上床的朋友
who was sleeping with his sister.
我是说比现在要简单一些
I was speaking in relative terms.
- 你怀念那段时光吗？ - 我当然怀念了
- Do you miss it? - Of course I miss it.
不过 对我来说 黄金雄狮的日子已经过去了
Well, my golden-lion days are done,
而对你来说 和妓女鬼混的毛病也许还在
but whoremongering is still an option for you.
不在了
It's not.
正是因为我变得专情 才闹出那样的事
Things would be easier if it were.
敬自我完善带来的危害
The perils of self-betterment.
哦！
Oh!
小姐
My lady.
哦 我们不是有意打扰
Oh, we didn't mean to interrupt.
我们只是找个暖和地方来……
We were just looking for somewhere warm to...
思考即将到来的死亡
To contemplate your imminent death.
那你可来对了地方
You've come to the right place.
要来口马尿吗？味道还凑合
You want some of this piss? It's not bad.
- 可也没多好 - 谢谢 大人
- It's not good either. - Thank you, milord.
我觉得这不太明智
I don't think that's wise.
战斗随时可能打响
The battle might start at any moment.
只能半杯
Half cup.
- 你呢？ - 不用 谢谢
- And you? - No, thank you.
我应该试着睡会儿
I should try and get some sleep.
你真觉得今晚有人睡得着吗
You really think any of us are going to sleep tonight?
来一杯吧
Join us.
行吧
All right.
少来点儿
Just a bit.
你们喝小酒呢
Well, what do we have here?
戴佛斯爵士 你也来一杯吗
Ser Davos, join us.
不 我不用了 谢谢
No, none for me, thanks.
我就是图这把炉火
Came here for this.
我想我在外边冻掉卵蛋也是等死
I figured I could wait to die freezing my balls off out there
在这里温暖舒适也是等死
or wait to die nice and warm in here.
今晚可能是我们在人间的最后一夜了
It could be our last night in this world, you know.
是啊 我很高兴你在这里
Yes, well, I'm glad you're here.
和我们并肩作战
Here fighting with us.
很高兴你从东海望活着回来了
Glad you survived Eastwatch.
来一杯吗
Would you like a drink?
自备了
Brought my own.
听说大家都叫你“杀君者”
They call you "King Killer."
某些人是这么叫
I'm sure someone does.
大家叫我“巨人克星”
They call me "Giantsbane."
知道为什么吗
Want to know why?
10岁那年我杀了一个巨人
I killed a giant when I was 10.
然后爬上床跟他老婆一起睡
Then I climbed right into bed with his wife.
你知道她醒来以后怎么做的吗
When she woke up, you know what she did?
她给我喂了三个月的奶
Suckled me at her teat for three months.
以为我是她的孩子
Thought I was her baby.
所以我才这么强壮
That's how I got so strong.
都是因为巨人的奶
Giant's milk.
听得我也想喝一杯了
Maybe I will have that drink.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
你以前总说个不停
You never used to shut up.
现在却像个哑巴一样坐在这儿
Now you're just sitting there like a mute.
大概我变了吧
Guess I've changed.
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing up here?
你觉得我还能干嘛
What's it look like?
不 我是问 你来这里做什么
No, I mean, what are you doing up here?
你加入了兄弟会
You joined the Brotherhood.
你和琼恩去了长城外
You went beyond the Wall with Jon.
现在你又来了这儿 为什么？
You're here now. Why?
你上次为别人而战是什么时候了？
When was the last time you fought for anyone but yourself?
我曾为你而战 还记得吗
I fought for you, didn't I?
靠 我操
Oh, for fuck's sake.
这下他妈的还不如参加婚礼有意思
May as well be at a bloody wedding.
小姐
My lady.
很高兴再次见到你
It's good to see you again.
很抱歉 上次我们分别时很不愉快
I'm sorry we parted the way we did.
他在你名单上吗？
Was he on your list?
有一阵子在
For a little while.
没关系
That's all right.
光之王终究还是让我们相聚了
The Lord of Light has brought us together all the same.
此刻属于他
This is his moment.
- 当光…… - 索罗斯都已经不在了
- When light... - Thoros isn't here anymore,
劝你别再布道了
so I hope you're not about to give a sermon.
如果你继续的话
Because if you are,
光之王可能会后悔救回你19次
the Lord of Light's gonna wonder why he brought you back 19 times
难道他就为了看你被我扔到那破墙外头摔死吗
just to watch you die when I chuck you over this fucking wall.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我可不想跟你们两个可怜的老王八蛋一起度过最后时刻
I'm not spending my final hours with you two miserable old shits.
那是给我的吗？
That for me?
这个还不错
This'll work.
上次你见我的时候
Last time you saw me,
你就想让我来临冬城
you wanted me to come to Winterfell.
虽然绕了些远路 但我还是……
Took the long road, but...
红袍女想要你做什么
What did the Red Woman want with you?
她想用我的血做法术
She wanted my blood for some kind of spell.
为什么是你的血
Why your blood?
我是劳勃·拜拉席恩的私生子
I'm Robert Baratheon's bastard.
直到红袍女告诉我我才知道
I didn't know until she told me.
然后她把我捆起来 扒光我的衣服
Then she tied me up, stripped me down,
让水蛭爬满我全身
put leeches all over me.
那是你的第一次吗
Was that your first time?
不 好吧 是第一次有水蛭爬到我鸡巴上
No, yeah, I've never had leeches put all over my cock.
是你第一次睡女人吗
Your first time with a woman.
你说什么？
What?
我…… 我没有…… 我没跟她睡
I... I didn't... I wasn't with her.
在君临呢 你睡过别的姑娘吗？
Were you with other girls before that in King's Landing?
离开君临以后呢？
Or after?
你不记得了？
You don't remember?
- 对 我睡过 - 一个？
- Yes, I was. - One?
两个？
Two?
- 还是二十个？- 好吧 我没数过
- Twenty? - Well, I didn't keep count.
不 你数过
Yes, you did.
三个
Three.
我们可能很快就要死了
We're probably going to die soon.
死之前我想知道那是什么感觉
I want to know what it's like before that happens.
艾莉亚 我……
Arya, I...
我不是红袍女
I'm not the Red Woman.
你自己脱裤子吧
Take your own bloody pants off.
这种感觉很奇怪 是不是
It's strange, isn't it?
几乎在座所有人都曾经和史塔克家族打过仗
Almost everyone here's fought the Starks at one time or another.
现在我们却都在史塔克家的城堡 准备并肩作战
And here we are in their castle, ready to defend it.
保卫它
Together.
至少我们死得光荣
At least we'll die with honor.
我们也可能活下来
I think we might live.
我……我真这么想的
I... I do.
我们从多少场战斗中死里逃生了
How many battles have we survived between us?
戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士
Ser Davos Seaworth.
黑水河之战和私生子之战的幸存者
Survivor of both the Blackwater and the Battle of the Bastards.
- 而我明明一点武艺都不会 - 嗯
- All without a shred of combat ability. - Mm.
詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士 派克城攻防战的著名英雄
Ser Jaime Lannister, fabled hero of the Siege of Pyke.
呓语森林之战的著名败军之将
Fabled loser of the Battle of Whispering Wood.
说得好！
Hear, hear!
塔斯的布蕾妮爵士
Ser Brienne of Tarth.
曾打败猎狗……
Defeated the Hound in...
不好意思 是布蕾妮小姐
Pardon me, Lady Brienne.
她居然不是爵士？
She's not a ser?
你居然不是骑士？
You're not a knight?
女人不能成为骑士
Women can't be knights.
- 为什么不能？ - 传统
- Why not? - Tradition.
去他妈的传统
Fuck tradition.
我根本不想当骑士
I don't even want to be a knight.
我不是国王
I'm no king.
我要是国王
But if I were,
一定册封你当骑士封个十几遍
I'd knight you 10 times over.
不需要国王
You don't need a king.
任何骑士都能册封骑士
Any knight can make another knight.
我来示范
I'll prove it.
跪下 布蕾妮小姐
Kneel, Lady Brienne.
你到底想不想成为骑士？
Do you want to be a knight or not?
跪下
Kneel.
以战士之名
In the name of the Warrior,
我要求你勇敢
I charge you to be brave.
以天父之名
In the name of the Father,
我要求你公正
I charge you to be just.
以圣母之名
In the name of the Mother,
我要求你保护弱者和无辜之人
I charge you to defend the innocent.
起来吧 塔斯的布蕾妮
Arise, Brienne of Tarth...
七王国的骑士
a knight of the Seven Kingdoms.
塔斯的布蕾妮爵士！
Ser Brienne of Tarth!
七王国的骑士！
Knight of the Seven Kingdoms!
我们有足够的胜算打赢这场仗
We have all we need to win this war.
我的军队训练有素 妇孺也不例外
I have trained my men, women and children.
我以前打过仗 这次依然要战斗
I have fought before. I can fight again.
求你听我的吧 你肩负着我们家族的未来
Please, listen to me. You're the future of our house.
这一点不用你来提醒我
I don't need you to remind me of that.
你在墓窖里会更安全 那些我们要面对的东西是……
You'll be safer in the crypt. These things we're fighting...
我不会苟藏于地下
I will not hide underground.
莱安娜·莫尔蒙
熊岛伯爵夫人
我曾发誓为北境而战
I pledged to fight for the North,
我言出必行
and I will fight.
哦 抱歉 我不是有意打扰……
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
没关系
It's all right.
我们说完了
We're done here.
表哥 祝你好运
I wish you good fortune, cousin.
多谢您 夫人
Thank you, my lady.
那是什么？
What have you got there?
它叫碎心
It's called Heartsbane.
是我家祖传的族剑
It's my family sword.
你还有家人啊
You still have a family.
是的 我也很想挥舞它保护家人
Yes. And I'd love to defend them with it.
但是我根本举不动它
But I can't really hold it upright.
令尊教导我成为男子汉
Your father, he taught me how to be a man.
教导我做正确的事
How to do what's right.
这就是正确的事了
This is right.
它是瓦雷利亚钢所铸
It's Valyrian steel.
如果你能接受它 我会感到荣幸之至
I'd be honored if you'd take it.
我将以他之名 使用此剑
I'll wield it in his memory...
成为守护人类王国的坚盾
to guard the realms of men.
大战后再见
I'll see you when it's through.
希望我们能赢
I hope we win.
- 我们最好休息一下 - 不 再待一会儿吧
- We'd better get some rest. - No, let's stay a bit longer.
酒已经喝完了
We're out of wine.
唱首歌如何？
How about a song?
你们肯定会唱歌
One of you must know one.
戴佛斯爵士？
Ser Davos?
你会宁愿死个痛快
You'll pray for a quick death.
布蕾妮爵士？
Ser Brienne?
不
Mm-mm.
Mmm...
歌曲名叫《荒石城的简妮》：简妮来自荒石城，
伊耿·坦格利安五世国王的长子邓肯·坦格利安游历河间地时偶遇简妮。
高耸的大厅里国王已远去
High in the halls Of the kings who are gone
简妮和她的鬼魂们翩翩起舞
Jenny would dance With her ghosts
为她着迷的邓肯娶了她，为此放弃王位，甘愿让位给长弟杰赫里斯。
那些她失去的人 她得到的人
The ones she had lost And the ones she had found
那些曾深爱过她的人
And the ones Who had loved her the most
后来邓肯王子死在盛夏厅的悲剧中。两人的爱情故事及悲剧收场被歌手、说书人和少女传颂。
那些已经离开
The ones who'd been gone
很久的人
For so very long
她记不起他们的名字
She couldn't remember Their names
他们绕着她旋转
They spun her around
在潮湿的荒石城
On the damp old stones
带走她的悲伤和痛楚
Spun away all her sorrow And pain
从此她再也不想离去
And she never wanted To leave
再也不想离去
Never wanted to leave
这是谁？
Who's that?
莱安娜·史塔克
Lyanna Stark.
每个人都和我说……
My brother Rhaegar...
我哥哥雷加正直又善良
everyone told me he was decent and kind.
他喜欢唱歌
He liked to sing.
会把钱施舍给可怜的孩子
Gave money to poor children.
然而他强奸了她
And he raped her.
他没有
He didn't.
他爱她
He loved her.
他们私底下结婚了
They were married in secret.
雷加在三叉戟河战死后
After Rhaegar fell on the Trident,
她生了一个儿子
she had a son.
如果被人发现 劳勃肯定会杀掉这个婴儿
Robert would have murdered the baby if he ever found out,
莱安娜知道这点
and Lyanna knew it.
所以她做的最后一件事就是……
So the last thing she did...
在那被血染红的床上 难产而死之前
as she bled to death on her birthing bed
将这个男孩托付给了她哥哥……
was give the boy to her brother...
奈德·史塔克……
Ned Stark...
以私生子的名义抚养他
to raise as his bastard.
我的名字……
My name...
我真正的名字……
my real name...
是伊耿·坦格利安
is Aegon Targaryen.
- 这不可能 - 我也希望这不是真的
- That's impossible. - I wish it were.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you this?
布兰
Bran.
- 他看到了 - 他看到了？
- He saw it. - He saw it?
然后山姆威尔证实了这件事
And Samwell confirmed it.
他在学城读到了这个秘密婚礼
He read about their marriage at the Citadel
甚至不知道这意味着什么
without even knowing what it meant.
这是个全世界没人知道的秘密……
A secret no one in the world knew...
除了你弟弟和你最好的朋友
except your brother and your best friend.
这对劲吗？
Doesn't seem strange to you?
这是真的 丹妮
It's true, Dany.
我知道
I know it is.
如果这是真的
If it were true,
那你就是坦格利安家族最后的男性继承人
it would make you the last male heir of House Targaryen.
你生来就有铁王座的继承权
You'd have a claim to the Iron Throne.
列队！
Form up!
站好自己的位置！
Get yourselves back!
衣柜字幕组出品
冰火中文维基：http://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com/
本集关键字：荒石城的简妮 错误的春天
高耸的大厅里国王已远去
High in the halls Of the kings who are gone
简妮和她的鬼魂们翩翩起舞
Jenny would dance With her ghosts
那些她失去的人
The ones she had lost
她得到的人
And the ones she had found
那些曾深爱过她的人
And the ones Who had loved her the most
那些已经离开很久的人
The ones who'd been gone For so very long
她记不起他们的名字
She couldn't remember Their names
在潮湿的荒石城 他们绕着她旋转
They spun her around On the damp old stones
带走她的悲伤和痛楚
Spun away all her sorrow And pain
从此她再也不想离去
And she never wanted To leave
再也不想离去
Never wanted to leave
如今我们能做的最英勇的事
The most heroic thing we can do now
就是正视真相
is look the truth in the face.
《权力的游戏》下集预告
夜王来了
The Night King is coming.
亡者大军已到
The dead are already here.
坚守阵地！
Stand your ground!